# Christopher Glinka

# Jr. Software Developer & Systems Analyst

#### Contact

Edmonton, AB (587) 778 8210 glinkachris@gmail.com

#### **Profiles**

Portfolio: cglinkadesigns.com LinkedIn: Christopher Glinka

GitHub: CGlinka95

## **Key Skills**

Communication Team Leadership Mentoring Project Management **JavaScript** React MUI .Net Core SQL T-SQL Java HTML CSS Bootstrap Flutter/Dart.js Node.js

Ling

Python

## **Summary**

An aspiring and enthusiastic Software Developer with 3 years of technical education in NAIT's DMIT program. He is a Concordia University of Edmonton BA graduate with a major in English and takes great pride in his ability to write. However, he decided that IT is where he belongs and flourishes due to a life-long passion for technology and learning. Due to his work at Code Ninjas, he has recently discovered a love of teaching kids how to code and volunteering for events that host local groups such as Big Brothers Big Sisters, Autism Edmonton, and Ukrainian Refugee fundraisers. Through Code Ninjas he also runs a weekly teen-night where they can have a space to interact and make friends with likeminded individuals of their own age and explore their interests and learn new things.

# **Experience**

React Web Portfolio • cglinkadesigns.com Worked on and completed a custom website that showcases who I am, my knowledge and my coding abilities.

- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and EmailJS
- The whole project is accessible across many devices and is deployed by me and hosted under my own domain through hostinger.com.
- This project was fun to work on and taught me more about state (the navigation bar), APIs such as EmailJS, and deployment.
- Other projects that I am most proud of can also be accessed and viewed through the website.

October 2021 - Present

Director of Education • Code Ninjas, St. Albert & Windermere Teaching children ages 6-15 about coding concepts based on an evolving curriculum, starting with block coding, transitioning to JavaScript and eventually Lua, C#, and Unity game engine.

- Assisted on the Code Ninjas Windermere team that was recently awarded the Black Belt Center 2022 award for being in the top 5% of the company.
- Leadership role on the Code Ninjas, St. Albert team that broke more

- company-wide records for a single location's grand opening. 70+ student sign-ups prior to opening day, then breaking-even and surpassing 120 active accounts within 3 months of operation.
- Successfully constructed and taught multiple curriculums for various summer camps, including Web Development, beginner and intermediate Roblox Studio development, Lego robotics, and 3D modelling and printing.
- Awarded the St. Albert center's 'Got Yo' Back' award for always going above and beyond my direct responsibilities, being willing to lend a helping hand, having consistent reliability, and attending additional events and fundraisers, such as Autism Edmonton, to help the company grow and give back to the community.

July 2021 – November 2021 Barista • Starbucks, Namao, Edmonton

January 2014 – March 2020 Senior Sales Associate & Key-holder • GameStop, St. Albert

#### Education

September 2020 – Present

DMIT • Northern Alberta Institute of Technology

Studying in the Computer Software Development stream.

- Dean's Honor Roll 2021 & 2022
- Worked on a team of 3 other software developers to create a mock web application for a motorcycle shop's backend system from the ground up.
  - Technologies used: C#, .NET Core 6.0, Entity Framework,
     T-SQL, HTML, and holiday.css.
  - Each member was given their own department of the application to work on and complete: Purchasing, Receiving, Servicing, and Sales.
  - My task was to build the frontend UI/UX, backend business logic, security, and data processing/transferal for the Servicing system.
  - The project can be viewed on my GitHub profile under eBike-WebApp.

September 2016 – April 2020

Bachelor of Arts • Concordia University of Edmonton Graduated with a Major in English and a Minor in Psychology.

 Excelled in group research projects that present data and important information in an accessible and concise manner, both written and presentation format.

#### References

Jessica Brisson • Systems Analyst at CGI

Email: jessica.brisson@cgi.com

Dan Mouris • NAIT Instructor

Email: dmouris@nait.ca

Shannon Stevenson • Director of Operations and Owner of Code

Ninjas St. Albert & Windermere

Phone: (825) 440 5485

Email: <a href="mailto:shannon.stevenson@codeninjas.com">shannon.stevenson@codeninjas.com</a>

Annabelle Syms • Director of Customer Service at Code Ninjas

Windermere

Phone: (780) 236 1536

Email: annabelle.syms@gmail.com